Guide to the Philip Wagner papers, (ca. 1934-1997)
Wagner, Philip papers, (ca. 1934-1997)
- Series V. Photographs
  - From box labeled France April 1937, September 1936 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    Jura Mountains, up steps from Rock cellar Clos de Tart, Clos de Tart, canal, unidentified
  - From box labeled France April 1937, September 1936 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    Aigue Moute, Nancy
  - From box labeled France April 1937, September 1936, April 1937 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    Solutré 9/36, somewhere between Macon and Vienne, picnic, Rhine below Tain - H[otel], Place Ville de Chinauf de Pape
  - From box labeled France April 1937, April 1937 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    Cassis
  - From box labeled France April 1937, April 1937 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    Bearne
  - From box labeled France April 1937 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    the other abandoned village so[uth] of Crest-sur-Drome
  - Roman theatre, Vienne (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Algerian soldiers, Vienne (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Confirmants, Vienne (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Lavoir Meursault, April 1937 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - From box labeled France April 1937, April 1937 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    Lavoir Meursault, Villeneuve les Avignon, wisteria Tain - hermitage, hotel at Tours
  - From box labeled France April 1937, April 1937 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    Between Paris and Sezune 4/20/37, farm near Montils 4/21/37, town near la Forté 4/21/37, Lyons 4/28/37
  - From box labeled France April 1937 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    canal barge near Vierzon 4/29/37
  - Ch[urch] near Macon 4/29/37 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - 4/29/37 road, Cantune Fr[ance], 6 p.m. (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Place, Sezzune 4/30/37, April 1937 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - From box labeled France April 1937, 1937 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    Aqueduct near Luyens (Loire) 4/30/37, chateau at Luyens (Loire) Apr. 30/37, near Luyens (Loire) 4/30/37, World War ruins 5/37
  - From box labeled France April 1937, May 1 1937 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    Tours
  - From box labeled France April 1937, May 1937 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    Tours 5/1/37, farmhouse near Loire, Sunday 5/2/37, at Blois 5/2/37, to Folkstone 5/37
  - From box labeled France April 1937 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    to Folkstone 5/37
  - Boulõgne or Folkstone (which?) 5/37 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - At Folkstone, The Austin in Air 5/37, May 1937 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Birthplace of M. W. Wagner, Mehr, built 1898 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Cousin John Sechartz (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - "to remember a Nice (?) evening at the Vieth's Oct. '38 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Jocelyn and cat, n.d., 1938, 1959 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Boordy (Box 14, Folder 20)
    pressing and processing vintage (prints and negatives)
  - Winter damage in St. Emilion, "Miss Giroux (Box 14, Folder 21)
    Negative of poor photo on p. 199 of ACS Symposium #145"
  - Vineyards (Box 14, Folder 22)
    icy vines, unidentified
  - Vinifera [Boordy] (Box 14, Folder 23-24)
  - Pruning photos - spring 1988, Jon and J[ocelyn] at the piano, pruning photos at Rob's (1) Derman (2) bud break, April-May 1988 (Box 14, Folder 25-27)
  - "Dr. Frank locale X-O Wolcott, July 1977 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Unidentified vinifera, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Boordy, n.d., 1980, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 29)
    Nursery, spraying, Rob Spring 1989
  - Vineyards, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - From PAV #10/1991 p. 224 illustrating Bernar article on East Coast vineyards, November 1991 (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - Jet flight pictures [Philip] (stereo slides) (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - 1. Walters Gallery slides, very early - lawn, vintage (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - 2. Beethoven house - Matisse, leaves etc., Oct. 1959, Pocomoke River 9/60 (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - 3. more Pokomoke & v14 Risfield 9/60 (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - 4. very old (1941) Boordy Onken (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - 5. Wroten Isle 4/58, Ann Arbor 6/58 (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - 6. wine bottles - experiments (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - 7. autumn and Thanksgiving 1957 (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - 8. snowstorm spring (Feb.) 1958 (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - 9. grapes Boordy - fall 1957 (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - BV tasting - summer 1957 (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - 2 view California 1957 (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - 10.-12. California 1957, 1941-1958 (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - Slides sent by Susan Wagner, 1960's (Box 14, Folder 34-38)
  - Slides sent by Susan Wagner, 1960's (Box 14, Folder 39)
    France, Maryland
  - Europe - fall 1956 Box 1, 1956 (Box 14, Folder 40)
  - Europe - fall 1956 Box 2, 1956 (Box 14, Folder 41)
  - Boordy, Philip, Jocelyn, guests (Box 14, Folder 42)
  - Boordy, Philip, Jocelyn, guests (Box 14, Folder 43)
  - "orientation 6 outline maps shown Ozark 1/30/86" 6 maps indicating regions growing Baco Blanc, Florental, Leon Millot, Ravat Blanc, Rayon d'Or, Seyval (Box 14, Folder 43)
  - One each slide of "physical" map of U. S. and Western Europe (Box 14, Folder 43)
  - Peynaud chart (Box 14, Folder 43)
  - P. W. office, vineyards [Europe?] (rolled negatives) (Box 14, Folder 44)
  - Father, Charles H. Wagner (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Mother, Patricia Grennell, 1895 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Philip, Robert, Ruth, and ? (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Postcard from Ruth, 1904, n.d., 1936 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Philip (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Jocelyn (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Family, Boordy, unidentified house, Jocelyn (negatives), 1979 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Christmas in Boston, Boordy (negatives), Fall 1979 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Christmas in Boston prints (Box 15, Folder 7-8)
  - Boordy, felling of big willow tree, Gower Fiun [sp.?] photo of Boordy in the Fall 1979 (color negatives), Christmas 1979, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 7-8)
  - Christmas in Boston, Bobby illustrating the new metal vineyard rods (negatives), 1982 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Christmas 1983, March snowstorm 1984 (Boordy), 1983, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - J[ocelyn] Birthday, winter at Boordy (negatives), 8/88-10/22/88 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Family at Boordy, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Sun column photo, Sept. 1972 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Philip Wagner (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Boordy (Box 15, Folder 15)
    vineyard, family gathering (negatives)
  - Boordy, March 1961 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    Vineyard, family (negatives)
  - Gall group at Sleepy Hollow (contact sheets and negatives), 1977 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Boordy, 1977-1978 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    Nursery Spring 1978 (new planter), Christmas 1977 Rangeley & Boston - Joe - 2 shots of Campbells (of York Springs) in May 1977 after Spring planting (negatives)
  - Boordy, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    Exterior
  - Boordy, November 1983 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Boordy (negatives), November 1983 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    Jocelyn modelling Hotte (negatives)
  - Boordy negatives, July 1, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 22)
    Equipment, family, vineyard (negatives)
  - Boordy equipment (Box 15, Folder 23)
    crusher
  - Boordy equipment (Box 15, Folder 24)
    vineyard, family, equipment (negatives)
  - Boordy equipment, June-July 1983 (Box 15, Folder 25)
    Cristal Filter Drum Liners, Mini Minta [(sp.?)], Phil visiting Baltimore - June (negatives)
  - Boordy equipment, August 1983 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Boordy equipment (Box 15, Folder 27)
    labidar/spinner/pumps
  - Stemmer (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - J with Hotte (negatives), July 6, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Grape processing and wine making (Box 15, Folder 28)
    unidentified, Philip at Boordy
  - Grape processing and wine making (Box 15, Folder 29)
    red currents [sic]
  - Gold Seal [staff] (from G. Cahoon) (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Taylor [staff] (from G. Cahoon) (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Grape processing and wine making, 1986 (Box 15, Folder 30)
    Mac. Carbonique, T/40 & G-bec, Miller, 4986, 5276 (negatives)
  - Grape processing and wine making, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 31)
    J[ocelyn] in vineyard & playing pool at Rangeley, the West, vineyard stuff [Good Cordon illus - (Tom)] (negatives)
  - Places (Box 15, Folder 32)
    unidentified (France or Germany)
  - Vine Propagation Nursery (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - Vine Propagation Nursery, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 34)
    October and November
  - Vineyards and Vines (Box 15, Folder 35)
    ruined vineyard in St. Guilin (Bordennay) [sp.?]
  - Hautvillers - view of the vineyard, center left: the Marne and Marne Canal at Rhin, right bank (Box 15, Folder 35)
    Epernay
  - Unidentified (Box 15, Folder 35)
  - Goriska Brda - Pluber wih 'Briska Rebula' MAA 1975, n.d., 1975 (Box 15, Folder 35)
  - Vineyards and Vines, c. 1980 (Box 15, Folder 36)
    Ripping out BX vineyard. Many poor nursery photos. Great shot of Adrian & Peter's youngest. Lunch with Cedar Point people. (negatives)
  - Vineyards and Vines, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 37)
    "Vidal 1983, Macatawa Vnyrds. it rained very hard during pollenation [sic] -- causing slightly ragged berry set. Vidal is one of the most beautiful vines grown in Michigan."
  - Vineyards and Vines: pruning Rob (Box 15, Folder 38)
    Row 42 E April 1988, Corson 1 side, Cna [sp?] on the other
  - Rob Row 41 E April 1988, Double Guyot (Vidal) (Box 15, Folder 38)
  - Rob E side April 1988, full corda (Vidal) (Box 15, Folder 38)
  - Negatives, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 38)
    Pruning, sequence of growth Rob
  - Green Photo Box 1: [Roll #1] (Box 15, Folder 39)
    "Experimental Miscellany. Wash. Expressway -- Freddie Graebel, Winery" (negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 1 (Roll #2), November 1958 (Box 15, Folder 40)
    "London/Paris" (appears to actually be shots of region around Baltimore and Boordy), Walter Taylor (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 1 (Roll #3), November 1958 (Box 15, Folder 41)
    France (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 1 (Roll #4), 1958 (Box 15, Folder 42)
    Christmas plus Sondheim & snaps of JSR, ELI, EVB, CP (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 1 (Roll #5), 1958 (Box 15, Folder 43)
    Fin Nov. en Arbois, Gander -- office snaps, Christmas, etc. (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 1 (Roll #7), 1959 (Box 15, Folder 44)
    Primary election (March), Gunpowder, bird Prettyboy, Peter - Anne, H. O./de la Rue (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 1 (Roll #8), 1959 (Box 15, Folder 45)
    Daisy's wedding, Ratoop - visit, Wroten Island Trip (4/59) (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 1 (Roll #9), May-June 1959 (Box 15, Folder 46)
    Ann Arbor, Wroten Island (Lou & Willie), chez Dickie, Portsmouth trip (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 1 (Roll #10), Summer 1959 (Box 15, Folder 47)
    Barbie visit July 4th, Fine Spin planter, Jwo & Betty, Jerry & J[ocelyn] at Pine (contact sheet, no negative)
  - Green Photo Box 1 (Roll #10A), October 1959 (Box 15, Folder 48)
    Trip to W., Md. and So. Md. - Dillen, Bernett Crain, Potomac, etc. (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 1 (Roll #10B), Spring 1960 (Box 15, Folder 49)
    Bottling - Freddie Groebel, Paris - Warsaw - Sunday in Moscow with Soldiers (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 1 (Roll #11), Spring 1960 (Box 15, Folder 50)
    Moscow - Leningrad - Free Market, etc. (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 1 (Roll #12), 1960 (Box 15, Folder 51)
    Moscow May Day 1960 -- to Paris and start with J[ocelyn] toward Saar & Germany, Marquet Thum (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 1 (Roll #13): European trip, Spring 1960 (Box 15, Folder 52)
    Paris - Côte de Blancs - Saar - Sept Saults - Binn (2nd week of May) good prints Moscow - type Riesling pruning (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 1 (Roll #14), May 1960 (Box 15, Folder 53)
    Germany manily, Alsace, England (Jim Bone & Thames Sunday trip) (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 1 (Roll #15), June-September 1960 (Box 15, Folder 54)
    Swariz wedding, lift-tote, French girls (Charles Farnari, neice, etc.), office flashes, CDI, EVB, ELJ, cats (contact sheet & negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 1 (Roll #18), Autumn 1960 (Box 15, Folder 55)
    Includes autumn of 1960, Pocomoke River trip, Wilber Teyler luncheon (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 1 (Roll #19), Fall-Winter 1960 (Box 15, Folder 56)
    Crisfield, etc., Spring 1961 - party for Frank Beirne, Fouruin Dec. D-NY (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 1 (Roll #20), Spring-Summer 1961 (Box 15, Folder 57)
    Lake Erie Island, Fouruin, etc. (negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 1 (Roll #21), October 1961 (Box 15, Folder 58)
    California (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 1 (Roll #22), 1962 (Box 15, Folder 59)
    1652 trip (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 1 (Roll #23), 1962 (Box 15, Folder 60)
    1962 trip (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 1 (Roll #24), 1962 (Box 15, Folder 61)
  - Green Photo Box 1 (Roll #25), May 1962 (Box 15, Folder 62)
    Portugal, O porto, etc. (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 1 (Roll #26), [1962] (Box 15, Folder 63)
    Unidentified (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 1 (Roll #27), 1962, 1963 (Box 15, Folder 64)
    A. A. Thanksgiving, Christmas, Latty visit Fall, Chestnuts November (at Muer), spring primary of Ruby (May/1963) (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 1 (Roll #28), 1963 (Box 15, Folder 65)
    Spring through December includes Wroten Island with Freddie's, return trip, Dr. Frank, Dec. photos of Phil (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 1 (Roll #29): Christmas 1963-Christmas 1964, 1963-1964 (Box 15, Folder 66)
    Visits of Richard Scotts and Françoise Fourdrian (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 1 (Roll #30), Spring 1965 (Box 15, Folder 67)
    Wroten Island (Wild Turkeys, puppy), shots of Miner Vineyard for bev. ed. "Wine-Grower's Guide" (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 1 (Roll #31), Summer 1965 (Box 15, Folder 68)
    Bob & Gwen, Paroissien/Harper dinner, Vintage 1965 snaps J. & Frank Grant (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 1 (Roll #32), 1965-1966 (Box 15, Folder 69)
    Christmas 1965, Rockport October 1965, blizzard February 1966, visit to Niagara Falls January 1966 (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 1 (Roll #33), Summer 1966 (Box 15, Folder 70)
    Milan, Vincenza, Ravenna, Venice, also a good print of Jocelyn at home (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 1 (Roll #34), July 1966 (Box 15, Folder 71)
    Venice, Ravenna, Urbino, Gubbio, Perugia (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 1 (Roll #35), July 1966 (Box 15, Folder 72)
    Orvieto, Porto Ercola, picnic - Roma (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 1 (Roll #36), August 1966 (Box 15, Folder 73)
    Aunney, Belloy, Lunder, Solutré, Corcelles, Gwen & Bob's visit (September), Einser & Oleno, loading of Ms. Alondru (cattle ship), visit of Gaunoux father and mother, sister, Gwen's last visit (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 2 (Roll #37) (Box 15, Folder 74)
  - Christmas 1966 (Box 15, Folder 74)
  - Visit to Reston, Va. (Box 15, Folder 74)
  - Spring 1967, nursery pictures, summer spraying (contact sheet and negatives), September 1966-August 1967 (Box 15, Folder 74)
  - Green Photo Box 2 (Roll #38), August-September 1967 (Box 15, Folder 75)
    Vinifera hawk flights, Salerski delivery, grape close-ups for catalog (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 2 (Roll #39), 1967-1968 (Box 15, Folder 76)
    Vintage 1967 (crusher-stemmer), Sue & the Margot Maques in Fall 1967, Dr. Frank Fall 1967, Miner Vineyard Spring 1968 (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 2 (Roll #40), August-October 1968 (Box 15, Folder 77)
    Pre-vintage, F. S. visit, Anheimer visit, Ch. Gay, Westfield, Rioja (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 2 (Roll #41), October 1968 (Box 15, Folder 78)
    Lograno, S. Sebastian, Oroissire, Ghouz (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 2 (Roll #42), October 1968-February 1969 (Box 15, Folder 79)
    Bordeaux, N. Y. flight, (Sugar Fox) Finger Lakes, March 1 snowstorm (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 2 (Roll #43), April-May 1969 (Box 15, Folder 80)
    Mother, Nursery, Kier's Waterfall, Susan Wolcott, Libby and Hogachy, Kronheim party (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 2 (Roll #44), May 1969 (Box 15, Folder 81)
    May 19-27, 1969 -- Prosser - Davis - S. F. (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 2 (Roll #45), Spring 1969 (Box 15, Folder 82)
  - Green Photo Box 2 (Roll #46), 1969 (Box 15, Folder 83)
    October-November, Epernay, Arbois, Morges (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 2 (Roll #47), 1969 (Box 15, Folder 84)
    October-November, Sion, Beaujolais, Bearne, London (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 2 (Roll #48): Fall 1969 through Spring 1970, 1969-1970 (Box 15, Folder 85)
    Anita - F. S. wedding, Christmas in Maine, nursery digging - Bogher [sp?], plowing nursery - Foster (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 2 (Roll #49), 1970 (Box 15, Folder 86)
    Sue's 1970 birthday, Penn Yan visit in spring (including snaps of Greyton Taylor nursery), dead Gold Seal vinifera (summer 1970), beginning to 1970 West Coast trip (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 2 (Roll #50), 1970 (Box 15, Folder 87)
    Jugoslavia -- Belgrade area and into Sarajevo, October 1970 (a few prints of August 1970 Boordy race meeting), (mm design) (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 2 (Roll #51), October 1970 (Box 15, Folder 88)
    Jugoslavia -- Sarajevo -- Dubrovnik (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 2 (Roll #52), October 1970 (Box 15, Folder 89)
    Jugoslavia -- Dubrovnik, Kotor, Slovenia, Lake Bled (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 2 (Roll #53), October-November 1970 (Box 15, Folder 90)
    Jugoslavia -- Slovenia, Zagreb, Paroissiens in Holyport (with photos of new French winery sign) (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 2 (Roll #53a), Summer 1971 (Box 15, Folder 91)
    Sam Moore and wife, Prosser, Bill Wolfe, etc. (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 2 (Roll #53b), Summer 1971 (Box 15, Folder 92)
    Part of Yukon trip, big birthday for J[ocelyn] in New York (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 2 (Roll #54), Fall 1971 (Box 15, Folder 93)
    Spain -- Sardana, Javea, Barcelona (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 2 (Roll #55), October 1971 (Box 15, Folder 94)
  - Green Photo Box 2 (Roll #56), Autumn 1971 (Box 15, Folder 95)
    Spain -- René Barbier, Mallorca (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 2 (Roll #57), Spring 1972 (Box 15, Folder 96)
    Misc. (negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 2 (Roll #58), July 1972 (Box 15, Folder 97)
    Seattle, Prosser, Victoria (negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 2 (Roll #59) (Box 15, Folder 98)
  - Shots of P. W., etc., August-September (negatives), July-September 1972 (Box 15, Folder 98)
  - Green Photo Box 2 (Roll #60), 1972 (Box 15, Folder 99)
    Europe, October-November 1972 (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 2 (Roll #61), 1972 (Box 15, Folder 100)
    France and England, Roumagousse, October and November (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 2 (Roll #62), 1973 (Box 15, Folder 101)
    Wroten Island 1/1/73, party at Pali (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 2 (Roll #63), 1973 (Box 15, Folder 102)
    Spring through June, Ev spring inflorescences and pruning, Mark Miller Ber M2v1, killed - 6.4c vinifera with Zeke May 1973 (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 2 (Roll #64): W. Coast July 1973, Napa Valley with Wolcotts, Pasco, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 103)
    Also Henri Maire visit & the Clarkes (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 2 (Roll #65): December 1973-September 1974, 1973-1974 (Box 15, Folder 104)
    Rangeley, Sue, load of posts, Knopf, JS26-205, Vidal 256 (negatives)
  - Green Photo Box 2 (Roll #66): August to Christmas 1974, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 105)
    Winery pictures (pressing and racking shelf lots), visit to Walter Taylor, Christmas in Brookline (contact sheet and negatives)
  - Vitic - Young and Grafton vines changed over, also homa inflorescences (Box 15, Folder 106-110)
    Somma (par[ent] of Sebastian?)
  - Drip irrig[ation] (Box 15, Folder 106-110)
  - Joe Heitz, J at Maynard A[merine]'s (Box 15, Folder 106-110)
  - Napa Valley (Box 15, Folder 106-110)
  - Cross-road overhead irrig[ation] (Box 15, Folder 106-110)
  - Dead Alizite (at home) summer 1982 (Box 15, Folder 106-110)
  - Spring 1982 another AxR #1 (Box 15, Folder 106-110)
  - AxR just before blossoming (Box 15, Folder 106-110)
  - AxR #1 (Mole [-lowen]) (Box 15, Folder 106-110)
  - Another AxR #1 in full bloom Male slower (Box 15, Folder 106-110)
  - Summer 1982 (Box 15, Folder 106-110)
  - June 1982 (Box 15, Folder 106-110)
  - Adobe soil near Sarna Rte 29 (?) (Box 15, Folder 106-110)
  - Napa Valley non-stop traffic (Box 15, Folder 106-110)
  - Off Sonoma (Russian River) Bynum Valdai (Box 15, Folder 106-110)
  - Adobe soil near Sonoma (Box 15, Folder 106-110)
  - Red vivas, graften over to white Napa Valley (Box 15, Folder 106-110)
  - Napa Valley, Zinfandelen new grafts (pct) (Box 15, Folder 106-110)
  - Napa Valley Cross Road new grafts (prints and negatives), June 1982, June 1983 (Box 15, Folder 106-110)
  - Vidal, Macatawa Vineyards, high renewal system, clusters right to the ground, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 111)
  - Pruning photos - spring 1988, Jon and J[ocelyn] at the piano, pruning photos at Rob's (1) Derman (2) bud break (negatives), 1988 (Box 15, Folder 112)
  - Jocelyn in Pisa, plantings, nursery (mounted color transparencies) (Box 15, Folder 113)
  - Keuka - harvest time (Box 15, Folder 114)
  - 1 shot of Charles F. and Dr. Frank (mounted color transparencies) (Box 15, Folder 115)
  - Grape varieties plus nursery plus Manor planting (mounted color transparencies), March-September 1963 (Box 15, Folder 115)
  - Grape varieties plus Manor planting (mounted color transparencies), March-September 1963 (Box 15, Folder 116)
  - Dad & me (Philip) (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - "on the back step" (mother and Philip) (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Mother, Robert, Ruth, Philip (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Ruth, 1904-n.d. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Grape processing and wine making, n.d., 1992 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    Siphon-aeration technique
  - Philip's mother's family, Philip in school, Jocelyn, Philip, Philip and Susan playing penny whistles, Sue Wagner, 1893, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Philip and Jocelyn Wagner with unidentified men and grapevine (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Philip Wagner, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Philip and Jocelyn Wagner with Mr. and Mrs. Jack Ripley, August 1978, n.d., 1971, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Sun photos (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Boordy exteriors, vinifera, working, products on display, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Boordy People, 1940, 1967, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    Group of men with trophy, workers processing harvest, vintage production operation, Boordy Vineyards Purse Presentation, August 26th 1970
  - Boordy, 1961 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    Contact sheets of vintage production operation
  - Boordy exterior, Philip Wagner, workers processing vintage, contact sheets of vintage production operation, n.d., 1967 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Equipment (Box 16, Folder 10)
    crushers, tanks
  - Grape processing and wine making (Box 16, Folder 11)
    contact sheets of various steps in vintage production
  - Fermenting tanks (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Swimming pool full of wine in Germany, 1960 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Tasting - California 1953, 1953, 1960, 1975, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Places (Box 16, Folder 12)
    Winterthur, 1975
  - Inglenook Vineyard, 1954, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Vine propagation nursery, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Vineyards (vines) (Box 16, Folder 14)
    Dr. Frank's vinifera on Keuka Lake
  - California vineyard region, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Taylor, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - John Klay's vineyard, Pennsylvania (Box 16, Folder 14)